[Music]
welcome to the second edition of the
outlook money insurance summit the topic
of discussion is the rise of bite size
insurance and the utility and we have
with us eminent industry leaders anand
roy managing director at star health and
allied insurance park das gupta managing
director and ceo at icsa lombard general
insurance and tapan single managing
director and ceo bajaj alliance general
insurance a very happy new year to all
of you and thank you so much for joining
me for this discussion
so bite-sized insurance is something
that is very new for the insurance
industry and with the advent of
digitization it has got a major leg up
in the last uh two years and it has
opened up interesting avenues of
providing cover across the landscape of
general insurance but it also leads to
the fear that you know somewhere in this
rush to buy low ticket immediate use
kind of policies the focus will go away
from the importance of comprehensive
covers but starting the discussion about
these policies that are really the talk
of the town in the insurance sector
right now um i'll uh you know so the
first question to all of you is what do
you think is behind the rise of this
kind of uh insurance may be part of you
could start with that
yeah thanks nidhi and thank you for uh
having us here
um you know
while there is a lot more talk about
bite size insurance now as you rightly
identified uh there is a lot more uh
awareness and maybe even advertisement
but actually bite size insurance
policies have been there at a smaller
scale
i remember back in 2006 or 7 we had
launched a 50 rupee you know outpatient
uh policy for the rural markets part of
our social outreach initiative program
uh of course it hadn't kind of scaled
into the you know the
uh urban markets at that point in time
and i think the point that you're making
about you know this becoming quite uh
popular now is as i said because of
maybe the advent of two or three things
one the digital distribution which makes
it easy to uh relatively easier lower
cost to sell these products
second is i would say a large number of
fintech players you know payment
companies you know aggregators uh you
know bnpl companies
uh who are looking to attach uh you know
contextual policies to their customers
to increase uh you know the the
relationship uh depth with their
customers so that i would say would be
the second uh major reason apart from
the digitization uh but the need was
always there and i think it's just that
some of these changes that has happened
in the ecosystem is helping us
uh do more with this kind of uh these
kind of products in the market okay and
then would you like to add something to
this what is leading to this kind of
rise uh of bite-sized insurance
according to you
i am going first after you
sure i just so
i will just you know concur with what
bhargav mentioned you know
the concept is not new uh i remember
also way back uh we started off with
travel insurance it was also a type of a
bite-sized product you know where people
could buy insurance for exactly the
number of days they would travel as
compared to what used to be earlier a
package policy where which was you know
predefined so i think you know bite size
concept has always been there but uh
now with the onset of you know a lot of
online e-commerce and
stuff i think there is a
opportunity to cross-sell and attach
relevant insurance
coverages along with the products that
customers are buying online so
i think you know it has become more
popular now of course but yes uh the
bite size product concept has always
been prevalent in the insurance industry
not so
largely as it is right now okay like
anand mentioned i think it's also to do
with the advent of e-commerce companies
like uh you know these your olas and
ubers with which you are seeing these
policies attached to really think those
are also a nudge towards this
so first understand this that are people
buying bite-size insurance or is it
bundle no before we
get into that is it really you know
taking off or is it the new thing or the
new normal happening
see one of the dilemmas for the
engineering industry has been across
ages people don't get up to buy
insurance
so i think most of the issues that let's
see if i talk about generations you know
being sold is what is mandatory either
by bankers or by law or which is
requirement no and health obviously has
picked up pretty good now which is not
mandatory but people feel the need of it
and they see the height new cost
happening so that's picking up
so bite size to me has been very
interesting a lot of it is bundle i
think the customer just gets it a lot if
you ask 10 customers that do you have
you do you know that you've got an
insurance with no this is right of yours
they're surprised to see if no nine of
them say yes yes i'm aware and i i
consciously took it
but there's some bites and issues which
actually has taken out let's say the
mobile insurance again the knee like i
mentioned health insurance took off
because people realize the need of it
and they felt that they should have a
good health cover because it makes a
difference no when you see this huge
hospitalization cost happening
mobile insurance again i've seen that
people see the need of it because
mobiles do break and they find that no
they're able to whether it's too
expensive and a lot of people buy fancy
mobiles and very expensive ones and they
see that uh going on so there i've seen
people consciously buy
but in like most insurance products i've
seen by size also most of it still goes
as bundle some of it conscious pickup
has happened now leaving that aside it's
a new distribution which has come
through because the ease and you can
sell the small ticket size without the
cost of selling it that's an earlier
time like fargo mentioned anand
mentioned that bite size is not new um
there were enough policies no i think
not even in 2000 i remember
early 90s also 1986 also you had all
this pa policies and all that and even
today a personal accident policy for one
lakh cover no death only cost you 40
rupees a year well is it not buy size
and such a no amazing kind of product
then waters will be by size so always
there button to sell a 40 rupees policy
with a distribution which was not
digital that time no it would not happen
because of the distribution cost
required so with the advent of
e-commerce with the advanced of for
distillation with this obviously small
ticket sized products can be sold now
and they're viable because you don't
have to spend so much on distribution on
that basis so it's a it's a phenomena
which is going to stay it's going to get
powerful over time anything but it is
also evolving like other lines of
business and that is my view on this
but
also i would like uh to ask you
gentlemen but uh
what what about you are saying that
distribution has become perhaps easier
because they are they're coming bundled
with other services but uh
what about i mean uh you know i take a
bite says insurance perhaps for a trip
to the airport and i did i don't face
any challenge the next time because you
know so many times it happens that you
know you uh book a ticket and you don't
take travel insurance a lot of times
most of us you know don't click on that
option of taking travel insurance
especially if it's a domestic but uh
do you think that this can be
sustainable in the long run as people
will get used to it because this whole
thing of renewal distribution is there
is no direct face that is you know
making you understand that you might
need it or you may not need it it is up
to you your decision whether you are
going to take it up or not so
do you think it can uh you know
translate into a habit everyone you want
to go first reverse the order
thank you vargo
yeah so i think what excites us is that
uh for us the biggest challenge is not
about products i think insurance
industry is amazing for us honestly now
i've been
industry but it's amazing with the price
they offer
the challenge has been the
need and awareness of it because these
are
low frequency and high impact event and
people don't think it will happen to
them no that is a challenge for industry
so the way we look at it is the more
people get used to having insurance and
they may or may not have exhausted it or
taken a claim out of it which is not the
purpose uh behind know that everybody
has to get claim only then they should
start accepting it but the more they see
things happening around them you know
let's say when you saw it happen people
really bought covet policies no i think
it's right it started
people see things happening around them
and they know that these are the means
through which they can get an insurance
you know on the fly you know uh really
wherever they're going there's a travel
insurance a lot of people de-listed
which is actually interesting if you
look at the cost of the travel insurance
on
any website it's about 100 rupees plus
huh
you're paying a ticket for eight
thousand rupees huh but for the hundred
rupees we will uh the either no take all
the tick box and uh not not do it but
fundamentally we think about it if you
pay hundred bills more also you know
you're ready to pay for let's say 250
rupees for a cup of tea in a in a flight
something i tell people jokingly that we
should carry our own tea bags with us
ask for hot water and you have it no
instead of paying 250 rupees for a cup
of tea there but for 100 rupees
insurance we will know
take it up
the way i look at it the more such kind
of initiatives happen the more know my
customers know are aware about it they
may or may not feel the need of it but
as the evidence level goes up as people
see it and they read more about it these
things will pick up so it has its own
journey neither so i don't think that no
there's something that we should worry
about it was not happening i don't think
that we should worry about no people uh
deep ticking we should make this
continuous effort of creating awareness
we should make this continuous effort of
offering amazing products to the
customers of high value to them and then
no i think as time progresses these
things pick up so that's my view on that
okay so
what do you think is is it really a
utility based uh
you know are these really utility-based
products and people will take uh take it
up like uh you know saying that
eventually the uptake will increase as
awareness increases etc absolutely i
totally agree because see
um
people are realizing that you know
people are buying more expensive stuff
uh people are buy uh taking more trips
and
bite size insurance is as
both bhargava and papanam mentioned it's
a contextual in nature you know whether
you're you're actually purchasing
something and you feel the need to
protect that purchase that you're making
and here is an offering which is very
very reasonably priced and you don't buy
you don't mind you know
adding that on as an add-on so i think
that's the context but uh you know from
a
uh i come from a pure play health
insurance background so from a health
insurance point of view you know
bite size is not something which is very
very relevant because i believe you know
at a health insurance con concept or
even for that matter for a life
insurance you know and
the protection plans should be
comprehensive in nature because see at
the end of the day you want to give
something which the customer will
actually derive the true benefit out of
it okay there's no point in selling
something for a very short period or
for a context and when there is a need
for the insurance it doesn't serve its
purpose i'm talking about health and you
know in general so i think you know bite
size
in health insurance is not very very uh
relevant as far as i am concerned but
what is more relevant is how can we make
the premium bite size
okay to the customer so that you know
they look at the product as a byte-sized
product so can we offer them an install
premium payments and installments can we
bring all this new
technology like bnpl and all of that on
the health platform so that
eventually it becomes a bite-size
purchase for the customer but all the
same time getting a comprehensive
coverage i think that's how i look at it
from a health insurance point of view
so yeah please go ahead now i will say
you know just to uh you know complete
the thought process uh picking up on
what tapan said i think one of the
beauty of general insurance is that
we can
conceptually cover
every type of risk that a consumer
you know perceives
and as
life business
society becomes more complex
new type of risks emerge
and really it's an opportunity for us as
an industry to create uh
products which uh address those risks in
a manner that consumers find value
which is the point that you know thorpen
and if you look at uh you know adding to
that point if you look at one of the i
think the cultural mindset of uh india
has been traditionally indian has been
traditionally a
uh society where family comes in to
support you right and as you become more
urban more nuclear
uh i think people begin to realize that
you need to fend for yourself as well i
mean you can of course you always all of
us depend on family for many things but
you do need to trend for yourself and as
society progresses uh people think of
protecting themselves for from some of
these uh you know new age risks uh just
to talk talk about couple of new things
for example uh you know let's say cyber
someone talked about mobile very very
relevant i mean 10 years back that
wasn't a relevant category of product in
a sense right because there was no need
to buy you know there was no mobile
phones in that sense uh smartphones at
that time
and you didn't need to protect it today
if you look at it cyber insurance um
you know the exposure and the risk
wasn't there 10 years back today it is
there and you need to protect yourself
so i think it's uh really uh your
beautiful industry in a sense that we
can actually cater to very very new
emerging types of risks
and we have to do it in a manner that is
contextual it's easy to understand maybe
initially a bit you know inexpensive so
so that people
start exploring and using them
and as that as people do that you know
the awareness spreads and your people
end up buying more and more products as
uh society changes okay so another
thought that comes to my mind uh
regarding bite size is that you know
when it comes to uh the rural and semi
urban areas or
you could call it type 3 type 4
i mean especially the low income groups
the small ticket size is something that
may attract them even in health
insurance even in other general
insurance categories but the other
challenge is that you know a lot of
these
you know policies are also since they
are bundled with say e-commerce
platforms and others there's an element
of digitization attached to them uh to a
large extent so
you know but they there may be
digitization challenges in these areas
the categories that i was mentioning so
how does that gap kind of how does that
come together in terms of uh servicing
of insurance or servicing of these kind
of products to these kind of segments
so anyone could you could take this
question please
i think we reverse the order again
all right let's follow that as a knob
yeah okay
um
so yeah i think that's a great point and
you know as i started you know all of us
have had products and you know we had
done some experimentation in the rural
market exactly the part that they're
making and rural market is a segment
where you have to make it
more affordable i mean you know the
entire market is potentially just a
bite-sized market
but it is in my mind a fallacy that
digitization and digital payments is not
prevalent in the rural markets at least
our experiences today almost 50 to 60 of
payments that we are seeing from the
rural markets is uh is digital payments
uh there are other
uh
um you know distribution models that are
emerging uh you know riding on existing
uh you know models for example the
government's csc platform right so the
csc platform is very interesting uh
outreach program to from the insurance
perspective to use an existing platform
to
again provide very low cost insurance
policies this could be standard you know
motor vehicles or tractor or you know
you know small ticket personal accident
or small ticket health policies uh
most of the processes are completely
digitized just to ensure the cost is
minimized otherwise you can't afford to
do it so actually it's happening what
you have to do is uh again
think of the customer at the end of the
day design the product that is easy to
understand consume and claim uh
so that
the experience is positive and you build
a positive awareness on the ground so my
experience is that you know even for the
rural market digitally you know the bite
size insurance is becoming very very
popular not the same type of bites as
insurance that is prevalent in the urban
markets but
products that are relevant for the rural
markets yeah just to add to that i think
uh totally agree uh because see
uh the key is the relevance okay keeping
the customer at the end of the you know
that's
keeping them at the center of the entire
offering because rural does not mean the
aspirations are lower okay the rural
markets have very high aspirations they
are looking forward to getting the best
uh you know treatments or best
facilities or best services uh what
other large cities are getting so i
think you know the byte size is totally
contextual uh and it is not market
relevant it is more you know on the
uh on the purchase journey what the
customer is looking forward to in that
context i think what we have to do today
is you know
uh to increase the penetration of health
insurance i think bite-sized products
are a great beginning you know because
at least at the younger age group we see
that people
look at these products more from you
know understanding what insurance can
actually cover because insurance as both
the panelists mentioned here can cover
almost everything today in india and i
think that's a very very good uh entry
into the world of insurance for the
younger age segment uh especially people
who are you know using these platforms
on the e-commerce sites and all of that
and probably try to cross-sell more
comprehensive products to them as we go
along so that you know they become more
protected in the true sense of the you
know the word and i think that's the way
we have to look at this uh bite-sized
products
okay
you want to weigh in on this yeah really
i think uh first and foremost too and
bhargav did you to that that to say that
district saviness is not there
in the rural side or no in the
strata which is know as we call uh
upcoming
is wrong
because i think if you just check with
know what is my domestic health is on
facebook by virtual vendors on facebook
and look at rural
india also i think we do a lot of
business there um most people are on
facebook and uh and if i look at the
sale of amazon
flipkart
is more in the tier two tlc than in tier
one no if i look at the bigger brands
being sold
it's more in the uh smaller towns so i
think india has changed a lot from what
we think and what we do still have a
view on
so obviously like anand also mentioned
that no the aspirations are there now
it's up to the industry how do we cater
to that which is relevant no and
contextual from that perspective
more than getting to products how do we
service the claims i think that is what
is very very critical no the
infrastructure or service that names is
what the industry and the industry is
doing a job margot did mention about csc
i think csc is an amazing infrastructure
setup and the government collaboration
of the amount of government businesses
happening beat crop insurance with the
government health business
the reach is there and the servicing is
happening and people are experiencing um
claims now and first is getting creative
so for me personally i feel that if five
years from now we have a panel like this
and all of us are here again
this question would not have relevance
because the market would actually have
become very very interesting very big
and very very powerful in its own way
because if the creation is happening
like i mentioned
people have wealthy to not they don't
have wealth and
like uh people like anand absolutely
strong infrastructure for health in the
smaller towns and cities no the build-up
is happening nearly so we just have to
wait and watch and i i think the
industry is working on it and we shall
see more of it happening and bite size
will also happen
in the places but right now it's mostly
government driven and you have this
smaller two-wheeler uh vehicles and all
which is happening but why not for a
agriculture pump set a buy set insurance
no why not follow a small like a three
month or two month crops you know small
like strawberry crop you know why should
not be which is for the vegas of nature
why should there be a crop you know
small by change so potential is there
and i'm very hopeful very i know uh sure
that this is actually gonna take up
pretty well
okay so uh one thing that you mentioned
uh uh mr single was uh claims so what
what what is the claims uh you know
scenario as of now because i understand
that
you know this market is not very huge as
of now it's still in its initial stages
though it has started uh ahead for the
past couple of years but uh what about
the claim settlement is there any uh you
know is there satisfaction at that level
because these are small and these are
you know a lot of people a lot of times
maybe you know i take uh take a bite
size insurance but
maybe because the you know amount is
small maybe i don't need it exactly at
that time how how much how many
customers are actually coming back to
make those claims and how much of it is
really getting settled also
yeah nidhi i think first of all let me
talk about the industry a small
heart of the industry and then i'll come
to the specific question that you have
if you look at the heart of the industry
the industries combined ratio for now 16
years i'm not wrong correct or wrong
it's been close to 115 20
to give you just a rough idea combined
issue it means 100 every 100 rupees
industry takes 120 is the outcome
no and for even amazing big e-commerce
companies which we here are so
customer-centric they lose five to six
to every hundred no here the industry
losing 15-20 that means they're paying
claims through the nose
still people have a lot of view on the
industry that no they don't pay claims
so i thought just park this point here
the industry place came very very well
and it pays it very uh very gracefully
also
so out of 100 customers you know the
claim settlement figures was really uh
you know good at this time they die
report that came in december
i think it's been the whipping boy of
everybody of the media houses of of the
ministers so i think it's a bit
unfortunate i'll take this
you know we had studied not just we as a
global consultant had studied all the
financial services sectors the number of
let's say bank account or policies or
you know customer you know customers etc
and looked at the number of complaints
gi industry had the lowest percentage
but even though the claim number that we
pay is very very large
back to you just to support
the industry pays amazing claims
99.999 percent customers would be very
happy with it no the point that the
grievance ratio is no it runs into like
less than a percent it's point zero
something no i forgot the exact number
they're very happy the ones were
dissatisfied because the industry is
already between boy and that makes a
noise that no this is not good now let's
come to the bite size one we have been
one of the largest mobile insurer no i
think we started very early on
and we can settle claims remotely
so it does not matter that no the mobile
if damage has to come to our
office or somebody has to go for a
survey there which damage remotely
messes the claim and transfer the money
to account you know
so claims do happen mobile claims do
happen loss ratio or mobile insurance is
pretty pretty high it is not that no uh
the losses and we all know nidhi
generally so many of our mobis do get
broken we try our best to save it with
the light no i think there's so many
jokes there somebody fell down with a
new iphone then the question is not that
did your bone crack or no is the phone
safe well no people know i think that is
the kind of protection tool but still it
does happen
so claims don't happen maybe in bite
size it does happen and i think as i
said some categories in which it happens
more frequently some do not have it like
a right insurance would be a very low
frequency but very high stability but
for something like mobile insurance it
is very high frequency and no and it
does happen and the assessment happens
remotely and the money gets transferred
you'll be surprised to know that the
transfer money can happen within the 30
minutes of the mobile getting broken
even if you are in the farthest part of
the country where there's no access but
at least you can access the internet
if you if you can reach internet and
you're in in a place like that like
sitting on top of mountain internet
connection is there new clay will get
settled no so i think most companies
have built up this competence so claim
settlement is something obviously that
is our main bread and butter if we don't
sell claims well how can we know um be
in the industry so i think we do that
yeah so no so the idea was more to ask
whether you know people are actually
coming for claims uh
yeah so i don't i wanted to ask you in
terms of health insurance so when you
talk about you know breaking health
insurance into bite-sized products later
uh what you talked about earlier about
this concept of how bite size can be you
know brought into health insurance how
would you uh you know how there is when
it comes to health insurance there is a
list of exclusions and you know medical
you know
medical tests and all that people have
to
go through to you know to be eligible
for a certain claim or a certain policy
or a certain product how would you kind
of uh you know marry the two together
yeah so uh in the context of health
insurance as i told you i am of the
strong believer that
the coverage should be comprehensive the
premiums can be bite-sized can be made
bite-sized okay and that's i think
that's the
combination that will stick with our you
know potential customers but uh let's
talk about uh
the current you know scenario in health
insurance and some of the products that
were introduced which will fall
technically let's say in the bite size
segment you know there are products
which cover specific diseases you know
for example dengue or chikungunya or for
that matter you know there are products
which covers opt
you know treatments alone and of uh
recently in the current context of the
pandemic you know the industry did
launch a product for the covering only
uh corona specific you know uh treatment
and i think that was really uh something
which was in time in the midst of a
pandemic the entire industry came
together to offer a product to you know
to protect the society at large which
was very
you know
what do you say vulnerable and i think
you know these are the kind of things
that the insurance industry and the
general insurance industry in particular
has done
but as far as health insurance is
concerned you know
i strongly believe that you know
customers should look for a
comprehensive coverage and
we will be able to make that coverage
more
palatable by making the premium bite
size i think that's that's what i would
like to stick my argument on because i
do not believe frankly that a
short period cover or a disease specific
cover for two months three months is a
proper uh protection being offered and
at the end of the day insurance is a you
know subject of protection so we do not
want to offer something that would be
uh not uh available at the time of need
you know and i think that's what i would
like to insist upon so anand has been
continuously raising this uh issue of uh
you know comprehensive insurance and
that is uh you know one of my thoughts
also that uh
parker do you think that buy side
bite-sized insurance in any way can kind
of dilute this market or the need for
comprehensive insurance especially when
it comes to uh health even personal
accident for that matter because that is
also you know which is a large cover in
the bite-size space
what are your views on that
so
let's look at different categories i
think what anand is saying is very
relevant in the health
segment
which is you know the segment that he's
talking about
and if you look at the general insurance
multi-line general insurance companies
we provide health as also other
categories of product and going back to
the point that i made that there are
different types of emerging risks that
are that are there
and
every single type of risk need not
require a product which is
very expensive you can actually design
products which are relatively cheap you
know and byte size and relevant for the
context of the customers risk and let me
give you a small example i mean you know
in the same you talk about personal
accident personal accidentally anyway is
a bite-sized product because the size is
very very low but
but if you think about even a pa policy
uh
when i'm traveling in a you know in a
certain terrain i want a policy for
let's say 15 days because that's the
period that i think i'm at risk
why shouldn't i
you know get a product like that i don't
see a any issue with developing and
providing such products to customers
because
it's relevant and contextual for the
customer we have to think put ourselves
in the shoes of a customer and think
about what is it that is relevant for
the customer and design those products
announcement is absolutely valid when
you think about your health you need to
buy something comprehensive but the
types of risks that we cover in in
multi-line general insurance companies
is multiple multi-failures it's not just
for health it's across different
categories you know cyber insurance you
may buy a policy which is even as low as
50 lakhs sorry 50 rupees and you get a
production of 50 000 rupees
you know as a consumer i am happy with
the production of 50 000 rupees that's
good enough for me uh if i want to buy a
cover which gives me even higher
production that's fine coming back to
even health
i personally believe what bite size
insurance does is make people conscious
and aware
there is an affordability issue
across different starters of society and
when you're first coming into the
into that
insurance consumption bracket as a
consumer you may want to experiment with
you know smaller products and then when
you realize that this is not going to
cover you for everything that's a in
essence a good entry point to buy the
comprehensive products that anand
rightly uh talks about so i think the
mood point that i'm making is
uh you know horses for courses
different types of risk that customers
have different needs that customers have
we as an industry have to develop design
products and give them in a manner that
is easy to understand consume and clean
that's what our job is so is it also
like something like what you're
suggesting perhaps is like creating a
a menu which is a testing menu so that
you know
consumers can take on uh go on with the
full menu later to understand the
comprehensive to understand insurance
the basics of insurance what it can do
to you how it can protect you and then
go on for a comprehensive cover because
even when it comes to these kind of trip
insurance and you know these small kind
of insurance policies there is always uh
this argument also that you could take a
comprehensive travel insurance if you
are a uh you know frequent flyer though
you know uh
right i mean you can take a
comprehensive cover and we see people
who buy covers for a longer period and
pay a bit more period on traveling
specifically because they travel a few
times in a year and it makes sense for
them to buy uh maybe a long term cover
so your point is absolutely
making the same point that i'm making
that you know i think it expands upon it
oh you know opens up the market for
uh for multiple
you know segments of customers uh young
millennials who may otherwise wait till
the age of 35 to buy health insurance
may experiment with some small ticket
covers and uh
and that builds awareness that builds
connect with with the insurance provider
and opens up the market uh you know is
my belief and that's a positive so but
what has been the experience so far
uh maybe you could take that uh is is it
really working like that that you know
people are coming for these small
insurance policies and understanding it
and taking it forward uh to say a
comprehensive policy or a you know a
policy that gives them
wider coverage
it's i think
any answer to those would be too early
to give no
so i cannot say that we have seen a
clear pattern about it
the point that bhargav mentioned the way
you said the tasting menu no before the
main i think it's a very powerful point
see somebody
and most people don't buy insurance
dollar the insurance is not only under
insurance but underpenetrated and we all
know about it no people don't buy it at
all now let's say if they get used to
buying it and they start looking at it
then they obviously would think why not
this no and they can afford it now
somebody going on a 15-day trip knowing
they must be spending at least 34
thousand rupees so they can pretty well
afford something which is four hundred
five rupees no so the unless i stand
differently by insurance and full blown
cover i think that's also an interesting
point anything we
underestimate this let's say bites are
usually talking of 10 20 rupees a full
interest may cost 500 700 rupees no a
travel insurance policy let's see what
analysis i'm talking about also
full-blown health cover it will cost two
thousand five rupees so the beauty is
that we're not talking about huge
difference
somebody spending about fifty sixty
thousand trip can afford a two thousand
five hundred full upload cover also no
know
if somebody's trying to pay 50 70 rupees
for bites interest now let me give my
personal example
uh today i may say that i'm over insured
no but i love to be over insured no once
i understand uh the insurance products
any insurance but you can think about
you know i think that we were the first
to launch retail cyber insurance my
daughters bought the first two policies
in india no
every policy you think of i'd be having
it for myself the moment you understand
the beauty of insurance i promise you
anything you'll buy all the sports being
it there are expensive policies when you
talk a full blown it's not like you're
going to buy a very expensive product
you're talking a couple of thousand
rupees that's all as a full-blown cover
and by say you're talking about a couple
of
like 100 or no 50 70 rupees
so once people start getting used to
looking at insurance
i have a personal belief that they will
go in for the full-blown cover but do do
we have a pattern to give you the right
answer right now the answer is no i
think it is still emerging as the
pattern emerges it should happen but
that is my belief
so another thing that i wanted to ask
you that you know
like you were saying you know
understanding of insurance is very
important but we do see that you know a
lot of people still do not understand
a lot of insurance policies uh let alone
life and health which are like the basic
even the general insurance even water
for that uh
matter which is uh you know quite uh
it's it's one of the most popular ones
because you know everybody has to buy
motor before they can drive out the
cars out of the showrooms so when it
comes to bite size insurance i know the
ticket size is very low so i might be
low but uh
you know in terms of
these insurance policies also do come
with their own terms and conditions it
they might be smaller and on you know on
scale and compared to other policies and
all so
how do you think that awareness that gap
can be filled
any one of you can take this question
gently you're absolutely right uh i
think enough uh has been said on the
fact that customers don't understand and
you know i think we make a lot of effort
you know i know you know daphne makes me
make in terms of trying to make it as
easy and you know simple for the
customer to understand but it's a it's a
it's a it's a task i think one of the
advantages of some of these bite-sized
products is
that they are actually even more simpler
than some of the comprehensive products
and when they're simpler the the
benefits are very very uh
if i can call it almost binary you know
event of this nature happens you get a
certain lump sum payment
uh if you look at insurance there are
two types of insurance fundamentally two
types of insurance one is
indemnification so your whatever is your
extent of loss people reimburse that and
the second is benefit you know whatever
may be your loss i will pay you a fixed
amount the advantage of the buy size
insurance is most of them are largely
benefit construct as you pay get a fixed
amount of money in the event something
uh you know
unfortunate happens right uh so let's
say a vector bond disease uh you know
you have a tanki cover of 50 000 rupees
you get 10 we'll pay you 50 000 you have
a mobile insurance mobile you know
breaks i will give you you know let's
say 25 000. so it's easier to
communicate and the other thing that has
happened is on a digital platform you
can actually break down the features and
the benefits in a very simple manner so
that it's easy for customers to uh
understand and and i think that is one
of the strengths of some of these bites
is product constructs that we see in the
market
i think mario put it very beautifully
the bytes are actually much simpler than
the comprehensive one now having said
that nidhi let me give you a very simple
principle i think it also surprises me
when people talk of complication of gi
products
why surprises me that if if we are aware
of just one thing
anything which is damaged
or no has pre-existing
or whether losses already know
happened or is happening
does not get covered i think if this
principally we we understand this
then whatever you're buying for actually
know would be covered subject to some
depreciation let me put no very simple
principle now when you put this two
sentences and apply it anywhere you'll
find that most of what you bought is
actually covered for
the dispute starts happening for us when
you go for these kind of segments in
which no you start feeling that no
the pre-exchange should have been
covered or my previous damage should
have been covered or i paid the prior
five years why should i get my previous
damage is happening i think that is what
dispute happens dispute never happens on
the product never happens understanding
i think so i think this also has been
which i say i heard of the industry a
lot of people say it's complex and i ask
them okay what's complex it's in a motor
car what's complex
your car meets an accident no whatever
in the accident happen will get paid now
you have scratches in the car that's not
an accident that's maintenance no
so what's the complex part of it
insurance curve companies will cover
accident yeah and anything in accident
will get stressed it's as simple as that
health if you're something of an illness
is already there with you now no company
no
typically would cover that so it would
just mean that
when you bought a policy and anything
develops later that gets paid
immediately you know so i think
it is not very complex against a mindset
issue which i strongly uh believe
and when margaret mentioned benefit
policies it's so amazing you know you
buy a policy let's say demo or you buy
for cataract and if it happens you get
the full amount paid no question asked
where can you get simple products i
think again this industry as i always
say sometimes you're surprised there's
talk of complication i ask people tell
me what's complicated in this no i think
just the two sentences i mentioned to
you just keep that as a principle
for any insurance and the name the
product and then see what is not paid it
it's all created up it's as simple as
that but byte size is actually more
simpler uh more easy and more straight
through i think because that's why bite
size will work that will not work i
think that's perhaps why uh what is
adding to its popularity also the
simplicity uh in nature and also the
utility because of which we are
discussing this topic also so do you
guys think that you know this this kind
of insurance is for everyone or do you
really think that it's only for a
particular segment uh maybe the younger
generation who doesn't want to look at
company who's not ready to look at
comprehensive covers yet maybe they
should but maybe they're not ready or
you know that segment which is uh just
ready for those low ticket size
insurance policies
uh parker could you take that
yeah so i i don't personally believe
that it's
designed for a certain segment but it's
obviously the younger pop
you know the millennials the younger
people who are actually
uh more digitally savvy you know
using olaf for example when you when you
have a
ride healing service uh anyone who uses
ola uber is buying you know some of
these you know one rupee policies etc
that you that you that you talked about
so coincidentally i mean you know given
the nature of the customer segment that
uses the
fintech and the digital and e-commerce
platforms
yes you are seeing more younger
population buying this but it is not
designed necessarily for just younger
people it is actually designed for
anyone who uses those services and there
is a risk that they are bearing because
of the use of procedures
so
you also think that you know it's meant
for everyone you of course mentioned
that you know your daughter and you but
you know you are over insured and you
end up buying all kinds of policies so
it's it's pretty much out there people
like you and me every everybody should
be taking up these policies when you
know taking an ola ride or perhaps uh
you know ordering in food
yeah i think
and i look at my family
my younger daughter and my father they
are the most digital savvy people
so i think again these are all i think
when when i listen now i look at
experiences i think the myths and the
reality is very different
so i can guarantee my father can beat me
to any kind of e-commerce sites any
purchases any kind of no
right-handing taxis or sweet i still am
lost at it so he's more he tells me more
about bite insurance than i can talk
about no from what is happening across
my younger daughter
so when you look at the spectrum i think
they both are very powerful the issue
which comes through is that uh
how are we as industry able to put
together things of interest for all
spectrum we should never think that the
spectrum of no customers would not be
available that is a that's a myth i
don't agree i think in industry how can
we bother the spectrum and how can we
cater to every you know
section of customers is what we should
be uh working on so and the work is
already happening i can see a lot of
products and different spectrums coming
through but i think we should cover the
entire thing not thinking that only the
millennials not millennials are getting
older now i think
they should know i think we have to talk
about the gen z now
i don't know
exactly
so we should activate it to all uh
spectrum but we should not think that
they don't they they all really you know
understand and look at it very well so
uh you know summing up uh is bite size
here to stay and what other innovations
do you think are beating in the wings
yeah of course it is here to stay and i
think they keep on increasing in size
and scope and as i said you know as
new uh use cases emerge new uh
you know products uh you know that
people use emerge new risks emerge new
products will get designed and i think
there is a scope for tremendous
innovation in in our country in terms of
uh
addressing very very episodic risks of
individuals and uh providing them
through bite size insurance i think you
know
as long as the uh the environment is uh
open in terms of alloying these
innovations i think there's a tremendous
scope for growth of some of these
products so
i think our industry that was very lucky
we cover risks and you see how risk
keeps on evolving so it's a never ending
process so every third day you have a
new risk now we thought
uh when we started with the
corona we thought a couple of months
phenomena now it's year phenomena now we
see people think it's going to stay a
phenomenon so look at any recyclers
which has come through or no it's
constantly evolving so
imagine which industry can talk of on a
monthly basis you have something new
coming up you know if you look at
catastrophic losses now happening north
five in a year when we were kids uh when
it was a rainy day in three four years
time and school used to get close you
should get so excited today even if
floods happen schools are getting close
no times have no completely changed and
every third four months is happening
so one the options of creating something
relevant for customers solving some
customers worries or risk is always
there's a continuous process
to the ease of process and the ease of
getting claims and getting the customer
delight
is always there it's a constant process
you need to keep on with the tech
getting better every day you keep on
pushing yourself and keep on innovating
to deliver on that basis third with this
bite size coming through
can you imagine the plethora of
insurances that can be offered well if
you tell me right now to start listing
down bite size that we can offer between
bhargava mean
i promise you for the next one we will
not stop
no from the same main products we create
100 bite size products no
no so the point is there's so much to do
and how do we spread the spectrum how do
customers you know
uh
relish what we are offering and see
value in it and how does it expand to
the next level is there so i think for
our industry there's never a dull moment
uh beat for innovation for things to
stay and bite size is going to stay and
it's going to become more and more
popular as time progresses because of
tech usage i think no people will find
relevance of a shorter division products
and they'll make it much more powerful
more beautiful my last question to sum
up the session was that you know what
are the innovations that are waiting in
the wings and uh is bite-sized here to
stay really
yeah yeah absolutely and uh you know i
can't better what uh tappan and pargo
has said they put it so wonderfully
because see
byte size is a concept you know it's not
something that is uh you know that is
going to go away at all because it's
it's a concept that's going to evolve
now probably it may not be one rupee 10
rupees insurance it may evolve into
something you know more contextual based
on what the customer demands and
customer needs are and from a health
insurance perspective you know i would
say that you know
definitely there are opportunities to
sub segment and categorize the products
and make cheaper offerings so that
affordable offering so that you know
more and more people can come into the
ambit of health insurance whether it is
in the semi urban areas or within the
urban areas itself we can look at you
know various kinds of offerings there
are opd products and dental products
which can be offered on the bite size
platform and
i think all of us are working on that so
as a concept this is not going to go
away most important is how can we ensure
that the services are the promises that
are made on the bite size products are
kept up so that you know the
uh
the stickiness of health i mean the
insurance itself will keep on improving
going forward and hopefully these bite
size customers in the long run we will
get more data as we go along we'll
become
a
full-time comprehensive customers of
having over insurance as stupid
mentioned
and making sure that they get all in all
comprehensive coverage in all segments
of their you know
lives so that's what we are looking
forward to thank you so much gentlemen
for throwing light on this new area i
mean a lot of people they might be
around like you guys mentioned that
these uh policies have been around for
long but a lot of customers may not have
known uh you know before one or two
years in the recent past so thanks a lot
for joining me on this discussion
and uh good day to you guys thank you
thank you very much thank you for having
us
thank you it thank you bye
[Music]